Guide to the South Africa Now Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Episodes, 1988-1991; Series I
  - Seventh Season (National)
    - Episode N710, 1991 April 3; 1 (Box 141)
      The episode includes: Nelson Mandela and Chief Buthelezi meet on March 29 to discuss ways to end the violence in South Africa, which took the lives of 2677 in 1990, the most recent attack by police killed eleven and wounded twenty-nine mourners in Davidson; ANC member Billing Amodela was gunned down in Zambia; the future of sanctions is discussed along with a look at what the lifting of them in the face of recent reforms is doing; Winnie Mandela's court case takes a number of new turns, among them allegations of police torture of Mrs. Mandela's co-defendant and the suggestion that Mrs. Mandela's motive was to protect boys being sexually abused by a white minister; war escalates in Mozambique and Namibia demands return of its only deepwater bay by South Africa; SAAMSTAN in Namibia organizes to provide housing for the many homeless there; an exploration of the recent refusal by PBS to air Globalvision's documentary, Mandela in America, an excerpt of that documentary chronicling Mandela's visit to Detroit is featured; the influential African Artists Fund works to find training and education for South African artists.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 141D)
    - Episode N711, 1991 April 10; 1 (Box 142)
      The episode includes: South Africa Now Best of Show: a look back at the history of South Africa Now and highlights of some of the best shows; quotes from Jimmy Carter, Jesse Jackson, Oprah Winfrey, F. W. De Klerk, Linda Ellerbee, Nelson Mandela and others; weekly background reports done to support and enrich stories.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 142D)
    - Episode N712, 1991 April 17; 1 (Box 143)
      The episode includes: South Africa Now: Best of Show: Part II: more "best of" highlights plus a look at the issues still facing Southern Africa as South Africa Now prepares to go off the air; overview of the story of the "Frontline States," the countries adjoining South Africa which have been the targets of colonial rule, war and destabilization; a review of the segments on South African cultural expression and artistic creativity of Southern African writers, poets, musicians and theater people.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 143D)
    - Episode N713, 1991 April 24; 1 (Box 144)
      The episode includes: "The New South Africa Now" final show: footage of George Polk award ceremony, South Africa Now is honored with one of the most prestigious awards in broadcast journalism; announcement that South Africa Now may be independently produced by a team of Southern African media organizations, followed by comments on Southern African broadcasting; broadcasting service needs to remain independent from control by any political party; black townships remain a battleground, violent clashes between Inkatha and ANC supporters; discussion of controversy over land reform and the Land Act; independent filmmaker, William Kentridge, demonstrates his innovative animated film technique with a short film about a man who gets transformed into a monument.
      - Duplicating master, 1 (Box 144D)
  - Special: Artists Against Apartheid, Circa 1987; 1 (Box 145)
  - Transcripts
    - 1990 March 14-May 16 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - 1990 May 23-July 25 (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - 1990 August 1-October 3 (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - 1990 October 3-November 28 (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - 1990 December 12-1991 January 9 (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - 1991 January 23-February 20 (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - 1991 March 6 (Box 146, Folder 7)
- Short Reports, Circa 1985-1991, undated; Series II
  The series includes a variety of tapes compiled during the production of South Africa Now. Many of the tapes include news segments taken from other programs on numerous topics related to the anti-apartheid movement and other South African matters. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape C3: Anti-African National Congress propaganda; Ted Koppel, "A Time for Candor, About My Father's Business"; footage from "The Media and Human Rights" panel discussion, Undated; 1 (Box 147)
  - Tape C5: Newsreel #1: Police Brutality in Bophuthatswana; The Death of Petrus Nchabeling; People's Education for People's Power; Newsreel #2: Whites Against Apartheid; Consumer Boycotts, Undated; 1 (Box 148)
  - Tape C6: Newsreel #4: Black on Black Violence; Beleaguered Last Hope (United Democratic Front [UDF]), 1987 June; 1 (Box 149)
  - Tape C9: Newsreel #3: Calling for Pressure; Children in Detention, Undated; 1 (Box 150)
  - Tape C12: "Namibia"; Mozambique film in Portuguese, Circa 1987; 1 (Box 151)
  - Tape C18: Artists Against Apartheid public service announcement (PSA), Undated; 1 (Box 152)
  - Tape C22: Peter Gabriel -- "Biko" music video (dubbed over), 1985 September 29; 1 (Box 153)
  - Tape C24: Race for Change and additional spots, Undated; 1 (Box 154)
  - Jesse Jackson
    - Tape C27: Trip to Frontline States 20/20, 1986 September 4-5; 1 (Box 155)
    - Tape C28: 20/20, Circa 1986; 1 (Box 156)
    - Tape C29: #66 Jesse Diary, Undated; 1 (Box 157)
    - Tape C30: #49 Jesse Diary, Undated; 1 (Box 158)
  - Tape C31: Anti African National Congress (ANC) propaganda "About My Father's Business", Undated; 1 (Box 159)
  - Tape C32: "Mozambique", Undated; 1 (Box 160)
  - Tape C33: "Crossroads Kids", Undated; 1 (Box 161)
  - Tape C34: Sojourn for Truth; Jesse Jackson on the Frontline, Undated; 1 (Box 162)
  - Zambia
    - Tape C35: Freedom House/African National Congress (ANC), 1986 August 23; 1 (Box 163)
    - Tape C36: Freedom House, 1986 August 23; 1 (Box 164)
  - Tape C37: "Children on the Frontline," United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF), Undated; 1 (Box 165)
  - Tape C38: "Africa: Alliance and Action," United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF), Undated; 1 (Box 166)
  - Tape C39: CBN report on Resistência Nacional Moçambicana (RENAMO), Undated; 1 (Box 167)
    The tape contains part two of report begun on tape C40 (box 168).
  - Tape C40: Resistência Nacional Moçambicana (RENAMO) propaganda, Undated; 1 (Box 168)
    The tape conatins part 1 of report continued on tape C39 (box 167). Most of the tape contains no audio.
  - Tape C41: Angola Stories, Downtown Community Television (DCTV), 1988 April; 1 (Box 169)
  - Tape C42: Reagan on Angola and sanctions, 1986 August 12, 1987 March 19; 1 (Box 170)
  - Tape C43: Nightline: Botha and Tutu, 1988 May 26; 1 (Box 171)
  - Tape C44: Effects of Bannings, Tape #105, 1988 June 24; 1 (Box 172)
  - Tapes C50-C51: Sunday Judge -- Albie Sachs, parts 1 and 2, Undated; 2 (Box 173–174)
  - Tape C52: The Today Show -- Angola, John Alpert stories, Undated; 1 (Box 175)
  - Tape C53: Conferencia de Imprensa, 1985 May; 1 (Box 176)
  - Tape C54: Winnie Mandela: Freedom at 70 for Nelson Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 177)
    The tapes contains no audio at start of content.
  - Tape C55: Nightline -- Savimbi interview, 1988 June 30; 1 (Box 178)
  - Tape C58: CBS Evening News: Mandela's birthday, 1988 July 17; 1 (Box 179)
  - Tape C60: South Africa: A Closer Look, J. Morgan Hodges, 1988 July; 1 (Box 180)
  - Tape C61: CBS News report on "Cry Freedom", 1988 July 29; 1 (Box 181)
  - Tape C62: Angola: The Struggle Continues, 1988 August 11; 1 (Box 182)
  - Tape C63: Trial of Ian Grey, Undated; 1 (Box 183)
  - Tape C64: Albie Sachs interview (Portuguese), Undated; 1 (Box 184)
  - Tape C65: CBS News report on South African backed terrorism, Undated; 1 (Box 185)
  - Tape C66: The Gods Must Be Crazy, Undated; 1 (Box 186)
  - Tape C67: St. Paul Sister City Community Project, Undated; 1 (Box 187)
    Transfer from VHS.
  - Tape C68: Covering South Africa with David Turnley, 1988 September 26; 1 (Box 188)
  - Tape C70: CBS West 57th St.: report on South African draft dodgers; CBS Evening News report of Mandela's release, 1988; 1 (Box 189)
  - Tape C72: "Documental Sobre Angola"; "Matanza De Angolianos Por UNITA (União Nacional para a Independência Total de Angola)", Undated; 1 (Box 190)
  - Tapes C77-C78: R. Lloyd, NBC Reports on South Africa, 1988 July-October; 2 (Box 191–192)
  - Tape C80: George Bush in debate with Dukakis on Angola, 1988; 1 (Box 193)
  - Tape C82: "(Amor or) Less About South Africa" -- Ray Navarro, Undated; 1 (Box 194)
  - Tapes C83-C84: Nightline with Dukakis, parts 1 and 2, 1988 October 25; 2 (Box 195–196)
  - Tape C85: Nightline report on South Africa with Allan Boesak, 1988 October 26; 1 (Box 197)
  - Tape C86: CBC report on South Africa with promotion for South Africa Now, 1988 July 31; 1 (Box 198)
  - Tape C87: Mandela background -- section cut for South Africa Now, Undated; 1 (Box 199)
  - Tape C93: Devlin transfer tape containing footage of riots in South Africa, special AKA music video "Free Nelson Mandela," and Nelson Mandela tribute from India, 1988 November 14; 1 (Box 200)
  - Tape C94: SYGMA Television (France) "the guerrilla in short pants"; report from kids in Resistência Nacional Moçambicana (RENAMO), 1988 November 14; 1 (Box 201)
  - Tape C95: United States children protest South African children in detention; interviews with New York pediatricians, Andrew Stern, etc.; news report with kids and mother testifying in United States Senate before Ted Kennedy, Undated; 1 (Box 202)
  - Tape C98: David Bruce and EEC [ECC?] (Afravision report.), Undated; 1 (Box 203)
  - Tape C99: PBS: Frontline documentary with Max du Preez in Senegal, 1987; 1 (Box 204)
  - Tape C101: Interview with Godfrey (child tortured in detention), 1988; 1 (Box 205)
  - Tape C102A: Children testify before U.S. Senate about detention in South Africa, 1 (Box 206)
  - Tapes C102B, C106: Christian Broadcasting Network (CBN) in South Africa, parts 1 and 2, 1988 November 25; 2 (Box 207–208)
  - Tapes C107-C108: Christian Broadcasting Network (CBN) in South Africa, parts 1 and 2, 1988 November 22-23; 2 (Box 209–210)
  - Tape C111: Nightline -- Kennedy giving money to Sisulu's family, 1988 December 9; 1 (Box 211)
  - Tape C113: Reebok Breakfast greeting, Undated; 1 (Box 212)
  - Tape C116: Boston Channel 5: Report on City of Boston's divestment, Undated; 1 (Box 213)
  - Tape C117: United Auto Workers (UAW) South African Embassy demonstration with Bieber, 1987 May 21; 1 (Box 214)
  - Tape C120: Music of South Africa -- Oblowitz, Undated; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 215)
  - Tape C121: SABL[?] roundup; World Report, 1988, 1989 January 1; 1 (Box 216)
  - Tape C124: clip reel, South Africa Now, 1988 November 17, 1989 March 29; 1 (Box 217)
  - Tape C125: Anti-African National Congress (ANC) tape with Rev. Rick Schmidt (from Africa Fund), 1 (Box 218)
  - Tape C126: "Race Against Time," Mozambique in Crisis (Oxfam), 1987 March; 1 (Box 219)
    This is in PAL format.
  - Tape C127: Interview with Albie Sachs; Sunday Judge; Secret Mission, Undated; 1 (Box 220)
  - Tape C128: "Borders of Blood," Mozambique Embassy, Undated; 1 (Box 221)
  - Tape C130: African National Congress (ANC) Video Unit -- selected clips, 1989 January 17-February 24; 1 (Box 222)
  - Tape C131: WGBH Frontline apartheid series part 4; Rose Moss home video in Pretoria, Undated; 1 (Box 223)
  - Tape C132: 60 Minutes report on the African National Congress (ANC) with Joe Slovo, Undated; 1 (Box 224)
  - Tape C134: Eleventh Hour: Bishop Desmond Tutu, 1989 January 31; 1 (Box 225)
  - Tape C135: CBS News report: Albie Sachs, Undated; 1 (Box 226)
  - Tape C136: Stetsasonics promotion, Undated; 1 (Box 227)
  - Tape C138: NBC: Hunger strike and Winnie Mandela stories, 1989 February 19; 1 (Box 228)
  - Tape C140: ABC News London: Gorilla tapes showreel; Till Death No Apartheid, 1 (Box 229)
  - Tape C145: CBS This Morning: Allan Boesak interview, 1989 February 14; 1 (Box 230)
  - Tape C146/147: United Auto Workers; Exterior Supreme Court; Tour of Alexandra Towns, Undated; 1 (Box 231)
  - Tape C148: South African Embassy video, "A Common Destiny", Undated; 1 (Box 232)
  - Tape C149: Kwitny #305 -- Zaire, Undated; 1 (Box 233)
  - Tape C150: ABC News: Integration in South African Neighborhood, Undated; 1 (Box 234)
  - Tape C151: Namibia / Jackson Swartz, 1989 March 17; 1 (Box 235)
  - Tape C154: United Nations Children's Fund (UNICEF), "Chain of Tears", 1989 March 30; 1 (Box 236)
  - Tape C155: Aberdeen spy case, Undated; 1 (Box 237)
  - Tape C156: Namibia on McNeil/Lehrer NewsHour, 1989 April 5; 1 (Box 238)
  - Tape C157: Late 1980s CBS reports on South Africa, Circa 1988; 1 (Box 239)
  - Tape C158: Namibia, 1989 April 3; 1 (Box 240)
  - Tape C159: Desmond Tutu: Trinity Institute Conference, 1989 January; 1 (Box 241)
  - Tape C161: "Keep the Hope Alive!: A Conversation with Father Gquiba, Chaplain of the African National Congress", 1988; 1 (Box 242)
  - Tape C163: CBS News -- report on Webster assassination, 1989 May 1; 1 (Box 243)
  - Tape C164: Nightline: Jesse Jackson and Falwell, 1985 September 4; 1 (Box 244)
  - Tape C165: Doctor's visit to Maputo Hospital, 1989 May 22; 1 (Box 245)
  - Tape C166: MacNeil/Lehrer NewsHour: Tutu, Boesak, and Naude, 1989 May 18; 1 (Box 246)
  - Tape C167: Allan Boesak's speech at Metropolitan A.M.E. Church service, Washington, D.C., Arlington Community Television Channel 33, 1989 June 16; 1 (Box 247)
    The same tape number was assigned to two different recordings.
  - Tape C167: Arlington Community TV Channel 33 -- Excerpts -- Boesak speech on Capitol Hill, 1989 June; 1 (Box 248)
  - Tape C168: Gun Runners, 1989 May 22; 1 (Box 249)
  - Tape C169: WBAY/2 -- Chikane in Wisconsin, 1989 June; 1 (Box 250)
  - Tape C170: copy of South Africa Now show #N306, 1990 March 6; 1 (Box 251)
  - Tape C171: V. A. W. (Violence Against Women?) -- Don Stillman -- Moses Mayekiso speech, 1989 June 22; 1 (Box 252)
  - Tape C174: WNET -- MacNeil/Lehrer NewsHour -- Albertina Sisulu, 1989 July 6; 1 (Box 253)
  - Tape C175: Carolyn -- Candace Award, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 254)
  - Tape C176: South Africa's Bombshell, 1989 July 28; 1 (Box 255)
  - Tape C177: Our Future, Our Desire; Youth Resistance in Namibia; Namibia, 1989 August 3; 1 (Box 256)
  - Tape C178: The Future of U.S. Uranium Enrichment, Circa 1989; 1 (Box 257)
  - Tape C179: File Footage: Savannah River Site, Circa 1989; 1 (Box 258)
  - Tape C179: #4 Afrocentricity panel (Chuck D., Spike Lee), 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 259)
  - Tape C180: ABC News - Botha and Mandela meeting, 1989 July 7; 1 (Box 260)
    The same tape number was assigned to three different recordings.
  - Tape C180: ABC News Mandela report, Undated; 1 (Box 261)
  - Tape C180: #5 End of panel and press conference, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 262)
  - Tape C181: ABC News -- Sergay: South Africa, 1989 July 9; 1 (Box 263)
  - Tape C181: #6 Press conference, Nelson George, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 264)
  - Tape C182: Inside South Africa, Undated; 1 (Box 265)
  - Tape C185: The Hunger Project, 1989 August; 1 (Box 266)
  - Tape C186: South Africa Government -- Inside South Africa, Undated; 1 (Box 267)
  - Tape C188: "Namibian Execution Story", Undated; 1 (Box 268)
  - Tape C189: NBC Nightly News report on South Africa Defiance Campaign, 1989 July 21; 1 (Box 269)
  - Tape C189: African National Congress (ANC) video unit: Radio Freedom; Zambia Honours Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 270)
  - Tape C190: World News/ABC report on oil and South Africa, 1987 February 25; 1 (Box 271)
  - Tape C191: ABC, CBS, NBC reports on Defiance Campaign, 1989 August 30-31; 1 (Box 272)
  - Tape C192: copy of South Africa Now show #N406, 1990 June 6; 1 (Box 273)
    Title on case, "Network Coverage of Defiance Campaign," is incorrect.
  - Tape C194: NBC South Africa coverage, [No year] September 3; 1 (Box 274)
  - Tape C195: ABC South Africa coverage, [No year] September 3; 1 (Box 275)
  - Tape C196: Botha resigns -- network coverage (ABC & CBS), 1989 August 14; 1 (Box 276)
  - Tape C197: McNeil/Lehrer and NBC -- Botha resigns, 1989 August 14; 1 (Box 277)
  - Tape C198: Casspir story, Undated; 1 (Box 278)
  - Tape C199: From Like It Is -- Jesse Jackson in Africa (second hour), Undated; 1 (Box 279)
  - Tape C200-C201: South Africa Now coverage of Namibia, reels 1 and 2, 1989 October 4; 2 (Box 280–281)
  - Tape C202: South Africa Now Mozambique highlights, 1989 October 4; 1 (Box 282)
  - Tape C203: South Africa Now: "Investigative Reports", 1989 October 4; 1 (Box 283)
  - Tape C204: The Oprah Winfrey Show: "South African Nightmares", 1989 August 7; 1 (Box 284)
  - Tape C205: NBC News -- Robin Lloyd spots, 1989 September 19; 1 (Box 285)
  - Tape C206: Oprah Winfrey Show (Dubbed), 1989 October 25; 1 (Box 286)
  - Tape C207: McNeil/Lehrer NewsHour discussion on South African election, Undated; 1 (Box 287)
  - Tape C208: Broadcast Monitoring Services, San Diego -- CERT [Christian Emergency Relief Team] member held prisoner, 1989 October 27; 1 (Box 288)
  - Tape C209: Beverly Hills demonstration in support of Namibia, 1989 November 9; 1 (Box 289)
  - Tape C211: McCrary report; South Africa Now report, Don Alexander, 1989 December 13; 1 (Box 290)
  - Tape C212: Channel Awards, 1989 December; 1 (Box 291)
  - Tape C214: [Northeast World] Productions -- Namibia Elections, 1989 September 18; 1 (Box 292)
  - Tape C215: NBC - interview with Sisulu, 1989 October 17; 1 (Box 293)
  - Tape C216: Jon Alpert story -- Angola (for ABC), 1988 April; 1 (Box 294)
  - Tape C217: Mandela on Donahue -- off air dub, 1990 March 2; 1 (Box 295)
  - Tape C219: Boeing 747, 1990 May 9; 1 (Box 296)
  - Tape C220: Beyond War Award Ceremony honoring Neve Shalom/Wahat al Salam, 1989 December 3; 1 (Box 297)
  - Tape C220: South Africa music, Undated; 1 (Box 298)
  - Tape C221: African National Conference -- HEART (Health and Refugee Trust), 1990 June; 1 (Box 299)
  - Tape C222: Green Peace: South African Toxic Waste, Undated; 1 (Box 300)
  - Tape C223: International Aspects of Diamonds, Undated; 1 (Box 301)
  - Tape C224: CBC report -- pilot; International Defense and Aid Fund (IDAF), 1990 February; 1 (Box 302)
  - Tape C225: Media in South Africa; International Defense and Aid Fund (IDAF), 1990 February; 1 (Box 303)
  - Tape C226: NANA -- documentary clips, 1990; 1 (Box 304)
  - Tape C227: Operation PUSH (People United to Save Humanity); B[ruy] Nesbitt, 1991 February 9; 1 (Box 305)
  - Tape C228: Champion of Freedom launch, 1990 April; 1 (Box 306)
  - Tape C229: Lusaka Mission; Somaliland elections; Tanganyika, 1990 August 17; 1 (Box 307)
- Documentaries, 1980-1991, undated; Series III
  The series includes videotapes of documentaries on a wide range of topics relating to South African society, history, and culture. The tapes were presumably compiled and used by Globalvision as source and background materials for the production of South Africa Now. It is arranged sequentially by a tape numbering system used by Globalvision and tape titles used by Globalvision have been preserved.
  - Tape D1: Killing a Dream, Undated; 1 (Box 308)
    This tape contains elements of documentary.
    See also: documentary, Tape D120.
  - Tapes D2-D3: MacNeil/Lehrer NewsHour -- "Apartheid's People" (Tapes 1 and 2), 1985 October 28; 2 (Box 309–310)
  - Tapes D4-D5: South Africa Under the Gun, parts 1 and 2, Undated; 2 (Box 311–312)
  - Tape D6: Any Child is My Child, 1988 September 14; 1 (Box 313)
  - Tape D7: Namibia: Behind the Lines, Undated; 1 (Box 314)
  - Tape D9: Rough cuts Cry of Reason, 1987 October 15; 1 (Box 315)
  - Tape D11: South Africa Belongs to Us, Undated; 1 (Box 316)
    Marked "for preview only".
  - Tape D12: South Africa Belongs to Us, Undated; 1 (Box 317)
  - Tape D13: The Discarded People, Undated; 1 (Box 318)
  - Tape D14: Namibia: Tell the World, 1987 May 21; 1 (Box 319)
  - Tape D16: Secret Government, 1987 November 4; 1 (Box 320)
    Marked as "part 2"; there is no part 1.
  - Tape D18: African National Congress (ANC) documentary -- Mazimbu, Undated; 1 (Box 321)
  - Tape D19: Destructive Engagement, Undated; 1 (Box 322)
  - Tape D20: Corridors of Freedom, Undated; 1 (Box 323)
  - Tape D23: Namibia: Africa's Last Colony, Undated; 1 (Box 324)
  - Tape D24: Winnie and Nelson Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 325)
  - Tape D27-D28: Namibia -- In God's Country (Parts 1 and 2), 2 (Box 326–327)
  - Tape D29: Peter Davis -- Remembering Mandela, Undated; 1 (Box 328)
  - Tape D31: The ANC (African National Congress) Method -- Violence, Undated; 1 (Box 329)
  - Tape D32a: Mozambique -- The Struggle for Survival, 1987; 1 (Box 330)
  - Tape D34: Angola -- And the Winner Is?, Undated; 1 (Box 331)
  - Tape D36: Mama I'm Crying, Undated; 1 (Box 332)
  - Tape D37: Classified People, Undated; 1 (Box 333)
  - Tapes D39-D41: Cuban Army film documentary (Parts 1-3), 1988; 3 (Box 334–336)
  - Tape D42: The Bombing of Khotso House, 1988 August 31; 1 (Box 337)
  - Tape D44: Inside New Jersey: The Namibia Question, South Africa and the United Nations, Undated; 1 (Box 338)
  - Tape D45: The Devil's Circle, 1983 October 14; 1 (Box 339)
  - Tape D46: Lusaka TV, Zambia -- Department of Information and Propaganda (DIP) --- Luanda, Namibia Week Special [South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO) tape], 1981 November; 1 (Box 340)
  - Tape D47: Yellow Cake Road [South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO)], 1981 February 23; 1 (Box 341)
  - Tape D48: Follow the Yellow Cake Road (Dutch version) [South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO)], Undated; 1 (Box 342)
  - Tape D50: Afrique du Sud: The Apartheid Disease, 1988 October 25; 1 (Box 343)
  - Tape D51: Namibia -- No Easy Road to Freedom -- Kevin Harris, 1988 September 26; 1 (Box 344)
  - Tape D52: Mandela (India), Undated; 1 (Box 345)
    First 15 minutes transfered on tape #C93.
  - Tape D53: Caesarina -- African National Congress (ANC) documentary, Undated; 1 (Box 346)
  - Tape D54: Amakomanisi -- documentary on South African communist party, Circa 1987; 1 (Box 347)
  - Tape D55: Children of Apartheid -- Sharon Soffer documentary, Undated; 1 (Box 348)
  - Tape D56: Witness to Apartheid -- Sharon Sopher documentary, Undated; 1 (Box 349)
  - Tape D58: After the Hunger and the Drought (Zimbabwe), Undated; 1 (Box 350)
  - Tape D60: Voices from Exile, Namibia's Hidden Tears, Undated; 1 (Box 351)
  - Tape D61: Changing this Country -- The Testimony of Four South African Workers, Undated; 1 (Box 352)
  - Tape D62: Biko -- Breaking the Silence, Undated; 1 (Box 353)
  - Tape D64: Players or Pawns report on South African sports, 1985 October 24; 1 (Box 354)
  - Tape D65: "Sunday Report" John Owen report on South African disinformation -- not screened, 1988; 1 (Box 355)
  - Tape D68: Tapes from Angolan Mission, 1988 December 9; 1 (Box 356)
  - Tape D69: Programa Opçáo: Kuito Kanavale I; Especial "Ruacana", Undated; 1 (Box 357)
  - Tape D70: Opçáo Kuito Kanavale I I -- Costa Gomes, 1988 September 23; 1 (Box 358)
  - Tape D71: Opçáo Kuito Kanavale III -- Livro aberto "A. Neto", 1988 September 23; 1 (Box 359)
  - Tape D73: Ithuseng, Undated; 1 (Box 360)
  - Tape D74: Last Supper in Horstley Street, 1985 October 1; 1 (Box 361)
  - Tape D75: Crossroads, 1985 April 9; 1 (Box 362)
  - Tape D76: Namibia -- No Easy Road to Freedom, 1988 October 21; 1 (Box 363)
  - Tape D77-D79: Inside the CIA (Central Intelligence Agency), Parts 1-3, 1987; 3 (Box 364–366)
    The same tape number (D79) was assigned to two different recordings.
  - Tape D79: Stockwell, Undated; 1 (Box 367)
  - Tape D80: "Signals" -- Program 18: Singing the Changes, 1989 February 3; 1 (Box 368)
  - Tapes D81-D82: Angola video, Parts 1-2, Undated; 2 (Box 369–370)
  - Tapes D84-D85: Abdullah Ibrahim -- The Brother with Perfect Timing, Parts 1 and 2, 1989 February 23; 2 (Box 371–372)
  - Tape D86: The Deeper Image, 1989 February 8; 1 (Box 373)
  - Tape D87: America's Defense Monitor -- Would You Buy This Bomber?, 1987; 1 (Box 374)